you all heard me say it before weight
lifting belts can be huge as you start
to lift some heavy weight they're going
to allow you to have an external source
to brace against that's going to allow
you to stay in proper form and may even
help you lift heavier weight now I've
spent some time with leather belts
hybrid belts well today I've got another
nylon belt ready to review for y'all
this time it's coming from element 26.
I've been using this belt for a couple
weeks now so why don't we go ahead and
dig into all my findings
oh
what's up my people it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time
around I've got the self-locking weight
lifting belt from element 26. now before
I tell you everything you need to know
about this belt from the price the
features the pros and the cons and who
should or should not buy one of these I
gotta let you know we've reviewed a ton
of weightlifting belts on barbin.com so
I think you should check out our best
list just go ahead and search bar Bend
best weightlifting belts and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
okay so there's a lot to like about this
weightlifting bill first of all I really
like how it's made from 100 nylon you
know it's gonna still provide the proper
support needed for a heavy lift but it's
not going to constrict you to the point
where you know you can't really breathe
that's obviously not fun when you're
working out and plus you know yeah it is
made of nylon so it's going to allow you
to stay pretty mobile so this is really
meant for Olympic and Crossfit style
workouts but personally I think you can
definitely still use this for your power
lifting movements this is really due in
part to the velcro strap right here it's
going to allow you to really have an
infinite amount of adjustments I mean
you're probably going to want to
constricting yourself too much before
you run out of adjustments available to
you so that's really nice and I really
like the pairing of that velcro strap
with the steel roller right here it's
going to lock itself it's really going
to make sure that belt does not come
loose on you whatsoever when you're
working out and that's obviously a
really good thing right there but it's
also really easy to take off all you
have to do is undo the velcro strap this
is going to unlock once you do that and
you can simply you know spread these two
rollers apart you can take it off in a
matter of seconds
[Music]
now with that being said there's still a
couple issues some people might
experience with this belt let's talk
about the fact that it is made from
nylon so it's going to be thinner than
what a leather belt would be now I
definitely still think you can use this
across all your workouts but you know a
fully leather belt is you know thicker
and it's probably going to provide you
with more support as you're going to do
you know a heavy deadlift or a back
squat you know those power lifting
movements I also really do enjoy this
Buckle right here but you know it's
probably not going to be as secure as a
belt that features a lever you know with
those power lifting belts you kind of
clamp that lever down and it's really
not going to move I still don't think
you're going to have much of an issue
with it but you know some people might
like that added security blanket that
that lever provides and lastly you know
this belt is not tapered in the front
that's pretty common when it comes to a
nylon belt there's some out there that
do have a bit of a taper in the front
but you know this could affect some
people as they go to bend over and grab
that barbell for a deadlift I personally
haven't had any problems with it but you
know that's kind of a person no
preference and you're not going to have
that taper with this belt
[Music]
so let's talk about some money the
element 26 self-locking weightlifting
belt is available for right around 35
bucks this is on the element 26 website
and it's also on Amazon if that's what
you prefer compared to the rest of the
market
it's a pretty average price now there
are some companies that are charging a
little bit more for essentially the same
style belt and I don't really
necessarily think that means it's better
now considering you can wear this belt
nearly every day you can use it across
basically all of your lifts you know
it's really versatile belt I think it's
going to be worth the money
[Music]
foreign
some of the features you're going to
find with this weightlifting belt once
again this belt is made from 100 nylon
so it's going to be pretty comfortable
but it's also going to provide a lot of
support for your core you know as you're
doing some heavy lifting now I really
like the fact this does have a velcro
strap paired up with this steel roller
Buckle right here it's going to keep
everything you know nice and tight and
it's not going to come loose on you as
you're lifting but because of this strap
you know it's technically a customizable
support with this belt so you can make
the belt as tight it really is loose
fitting as you please which is really
cool now I don't think you're going to
have any durability issues with this
belt whatsoever especially you know with
that steel roller Buckle but element 26
does toss in a lifetime warranty with
this belt so if anything happens on the
manufacturing side you notice any
defects
just notify them send it back they'll
send you a new one it's really easily
done now this does have a four inch wide
profile so once again it's not tapered
in the front which could be a bit of an
annoyance for some people but honestly
you're going to be really mobile with
this belt which is kind of what it's
designed to do this belt is available in
eight different color ways obviously we
have black right here but it's also
available in navy blue tan green red
pink purple there's a lot of different
options out there for you to match any
gear that you may have this belt is also
available in six different sizes ranging
from extra small all the way up to
double XL so there's an option for
basically everybody out there and
remember whenever you go to measure
yourself for this belt make sure you
measure around your belly button because
that's where the belt's gonna be
[Music]
okay so let's go and do a quick walk
around with this weightlifting bill you
know once again this belt is made from
100 nylon so as you can see you know
it's really flexible it's going to allow
you to stay really mobile which is
really nice you know once again this is
kind of meant for Olympic and Crossfit
style workouts where you are being
really explosive so this is going to
come in handy I really like the pairing
of this velcro strap with this steel
roller buckle you know once you've got
this belt slid in here you know it's
going to clamp down on that strap and
it's not going to come loose whatsoever
but because you do have this velcro as
you can hear you know it's really just
gonna be an added security blanket and
it's you know make sure that belt is not
going to come loose on you as you're
working out now whenever you go to put
it on remember it goes around your belly
button and not your hips you want your
core to have the most support possible
so just take your strap
slide it into the buckle
make it go between these two rollers
right here and then you want to make
sure everything's lined up
properly and then just keep pulling
really until you can't anymore or
however tight you want it
and you're good to go
[Music]
okay so who should purchase this weight
lifting belt well let's talk about the
versatility you know if you're looking
for a belt that can be used basically
across all of your lifts I think you
found your match right here it's
comfortable it allows you to breathe and
it's going to provide your core with the
proper support that you need for pretty
much all of your lifts I also really
like this velcro strap right here you
know it's going to basically allow you
to get customizable support and get that
right amount of pressure that you want
on your core and let's stick with the
design you know that velcro strap paired
up with this steel roller Buckle right
here you know this I don't think you're
gonna have any problems with this belt
coming loose on you on its own and it's
also really easy to take off because of
those two features right there
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase this belt it really
just boils down to personal preference
and your style of lifting now let's talk
about style of lifting first you know if
you're a power lifter that's that's
mainly what you're doing might be better
off with a fully leather belt they're
thicker and they probably do provide
more support now element 26 does not
have a fully leather belt but they do
have a hybrid belt that you might want
to check out
now let's talk about personal preference
right so you know once again this belt
is not tapered in the front so people
just you know prefer that and if that's
you know something you want I'd suggest
browsing some other options and lastly
right here you know with personal
preference is the design you know the
velcro strap and the steel roller Buckle
I don't think you're gonna have any
problems with this belt in terms of it
you know coming loose on you but you
know some people like I said earlier
just have the personal preference for a
belt that features a lever
[Music]
that's all I got for you guys today on
the element 26 self-locking
weightlifting bill I personally think
this is a great belt for you to consider
it's highly versatile you can wear it
across basically all of your workouts
the velcro strap and that self locking
Buckle right here makes it super easy to
find the exact amount of support that
you need in just a matter of seconds
however it might not be the best option
for people who are focusing specifically
on power lifting movements but at the
end of the day you know this is a really
solid belt that can be worn by people of
all shapes and sizes thanks for watching
everybody I hope this video was really
helpful and I was able to answer any
questions you may have about this belt
as always stay posted for my next review
but for now head over to barbin.com and
you can read more about this product
just go and search bar Bend element 26
self-locking weightlifting belt review
you can find all the details everything
that we discussed here today I'll see
y'all next time
[Music]